Guide to the Salo W. Baron Papers, 1900-1980
Department of Special Collections
Baron, Salo W. Papers,
1900-1980
M0580
Baron, Salo W.
ca. 398 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The Baron Papers comprise the personal, professional, and research material of Salo Baron and occupy approximately 398 linear feet. As of July 1992 the papers total 714 boxes and are arranged in 11 series, including correspondence, personal/biographical, archival materials, subject, manuscripts, notecards, pamphlets, reprints, and books, manuscripts (other authors), notes, photo and audio-visual.
Administrative Information
Access
None.
Acquisition Information
Purchased 1986 and 1990.
Provenance
Acquired from Salo W. Baron, 1986 and 1990.
Biography
Salo Wittmayer Baron was instrumental in establishing Jewish Studies as an academic discipline in the United States. An extraordinarily prolific historian, Baron also played an exceptional role in American Jewish organizational life. Baron was born in 1895 in Tarnow, now in Poland but then part of Austrian Galicia. His parents, Elias Baron and Minna Wittmayer Baron, were orthodox Jews, and Elias Baron was a banker and Jewish community leader. Salo Baron had two sisters: Gisa (1892-1943) and Tanya (Tania, "Toni") (1898-?). Both Gisa and the parents died in the Holocaust in 1943. Studying at the University of Vienna, Baron earned doctorates in history (1917), political science (1922), and law (1923). Baron also completed a rabbinical degree from the Jewish Theological Seminary in Vienna in 1920. After teaching at the Juedisches Paedagogium in Vienna from 1919 to 1926, Baron left for the United States, where he joined the faculty of the Jewish Institute of Religion in New York. Baron was offered the newly-created Miller Chair of Jewish History, Literature, and Institutions in 1930 by Columbia University, where he remained for the rest of his career (emeritus after 1963). In 1936 Baron and Morris R. Cohen founded the Conference on Jewish Relations (later called the Conference on Jewish Social Studies), which publishes the journal Jewish Social Studies. The author of more than a dozen monographs and over 500 articles on Jewish history, Baron had an extraordinary range and scope. He was at home in ancient, medieval, and modern history and could read twenty languages. His magnum opus was A Social and Religious History of the Jews, which filled 18 volumes. Baron saw his scholarship as a corrective to what he termed "the lachrymose conception of Jewish history." His work focused on the social history and cultural accomplishments of the Jews rather than on suffering and pogroms. Baron also sought to reintegrate religious experience into the historical fabric of Jewish life. Beginning with his work on the Permanent Minorities Commission of the League of Nations in 1925, Baron served on various international committees during his long career. He founded and directed Jewish Cultural Reconstruction, an organization dedicated to identifying and reclaiming Jewish cultural patrimony plundered by the Nazis. At the invitation of Ben Gurion, Baron testified at the Eichmann trial in 1961. In addition, Baron directed or served as trustee for several academic institutions and organizations in this country and in Israel.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
The Baron Papers comprise the personal, professional, and research material of Salo Baron and occupy approximately 398 linear feet.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Abramsky, Chimen, 1916-; Adler, Cyrus, 1863-1940.; Altmann, Alexander, 1906-; Ankori, Zvi, 1920-; Aptowitzer, Victor, 1871-1942.; Arendt, Hannah.; Baeck, Leo, 1873-1956.; Barzilay, Isaac, 1915-; Ben-Horin, Meir, 1918-; Bernstein, S. (Simon), b. 1884.; Blau, Joseph L. (Joseph Leon), 1909-1986.; Blumenfield, Samuel U., 1901-1972.; Blumenkranz, Bernhard.; Cohen, Arthur Allen, 1928-; Cohen, Morris Raphael, 1880-1947.; Damask, Emil.; Davis, Moshe.; Diesendruk, Zvi.; Duker, Abraham.; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955.; Feigin, Samuel I. (Samuel Isaac), 1893-1950.; Finkelstein, Louis, 1895-; Friedmann, Philip, 1901-1960.; Fuks, Leo.; Gandz, Solomon.; Gartner, Lloyd P., 1927-; Glatzer, Nahum Norbert, 1903-; Goitein, S.D., 1900-; Goldmann, Nahum, 1895-1982.; Grayzel, Solomon, 1896-1980.; Halpern, Ben.; Halpern, Israel, 1910-; Handlin, Oscar, 1915-; Hertzberg, Arthur.; Janowsky, Oskar.; Kaplan, Jacob.; Karp, Abraham J.; Kisch, Guido, 1889-; Knapp, Russel.; Kohut, George Alexander, 1874-1933.; Konvitz, Milton Ridvas, 1908-; Lieberman, Saul, 1898-; Mahler, Raphael, 1899-; Marcus, Jacob Rader, 1896-; Marx, Alexander, 1878-1953.; Netanyahu, Benzion.; Neusner, Jacob, 1932-; Oelsner, Toni.; Orlinsky, Harry, Meyer, 1908-; Pinson, Koppel.; Prinz, Joachim, 1902-; Roth, Cecil, 1899-1970.; Scholem, Gershom Gerhard, 1897-; Silberschlag, Eisig, 1903-; Spiegel, Shalom, 1899-; Starr, Joshua, 1907-1949.; Steinberg, Aaron, 1891-1975.; Stern, Selma, 1890-; Tal, Uriel.; Tartakower, Aryeh, 1897-1982.; Tèaubler, Eugen, 1879-1953.; Twersky, Isadore.; Wischnitzer, Mark, 1882-1955.; Wischnitzer, Rachel, 1885-1989.; Wise, George Schneiweis, 1906-; Wise, Stephen Samuel, 1874-1949.; Yerushalmi, Yosef Hayim, 1932-; American Jewish Committee.; American Academy for Jewish Research.; American Jewish Congress.; American Jewish Historical Society.; Columbia University. Center for Israel and Jewish Studies.; Conference on Jewish Cultural Reconstruction.; Conference on Jewish Material Claims Against Germany.; Conference on Jewish Relations (U.S.); Conference on Jewish Social Studies (U.S.); Emergency Committee for Displaced German Scholars.; Hebrew Union College (Cincinnati); Hebrew University (Israel); Institute of Jewish Religion (New York); Jewish Cultural Reconstruction, Inc.; Jewish Pubication Society.; Jewish Theological Seminary (New York); Memorial Foundation for Jewish Culture.; National Foundation for Jewish Culture.; National Jewish Welfare Board.; Tel-Aviv University (Israel); Training Bureau for Jewish Communal Service.; Union Theological Seminary (New York); World Jewish Congress.; YIVO.; Jews--History.; Jewish studies.
Collection Contents
- Series 1: Correspondence, 70 linear ft. (140 boxes)
  Measuring 70 linear feet, the correspondence of Salo W. Baron has an extraordinary range and depth. Baron's first letters are from before the First World War, and he was an energetic correspondent until his death in 1989. The scope of the correspondence is quite broad, covering personal, professional, and financial matters. Because Baron generally kept copies of his outgoing correspondence, all of these materials are very rich. Although the correspondence is largely in English, there are many letters in Hebrew and German as well as several in Polish, French, Spanish, Portuguese, and Italian. The overview on page 12 summarizes the general organization of the correspondence, which is described in more detail below.
  Although Baron filed most of his correspondence separately, some letters escaped this system. In sorting through the Baron Papers as a whole, most of the correspondence, filed or not, was removed. Nevertheless some letters were left in other series of the collection (see especially the manuscripts and subject series) because of the information they provided on the specific materials they accompanied. In the correspondence series, some noncorrespondence materials (such as financial reports) are included, mainly because these items were originally filed with the correspondence. To the greatest degree possible Baron's letters have been kept in their original order. Baron maintained two residences, one in Canaan, Connecticut and the other in New York City, and thus two separate files of letters. This division has been preserved here, so that the first part of the correspondence is labelled as the Canaan files and the second as the New York files. Divided into these two parts, the correspondence is then organized more or less chronologically. Within these chronological divisions, the letters are generally arranged alphabetically by the correspondent's name or institutional affiliation. The title of each folder is taken directly from Baron's own filing system in the vast majority of cases. This means that the dates given in the folder title are often inaccurate. The range of dates provided in the "Years" column of the user's guide reflects the folder contents much more accurately. When only incoming or outgoing correspondence is contained in a folder, this is generally noted in the user's guide; when both incoming and outgoing letters are included, no special note is made. The letters in Hebrew, which are scattered throughout the correspondence, pose special difficulties. Hebrew letters that are filed by correspondent in their own folders are included in the user's guide. However, other letters are not listed because the collection's processors cannot read Hebrew. Still, some of these correspondents maynonetheless be included in the user's guide because Baron often answered his Hebrew correspondence in English, since it was easier to dictate. In the correspondence there are often small white pieces of paper with lists of names on them. It seems that these were made by Baron to show which items he had removed for use in writing his autobiography. Materials pertaining to this autobiography can be found in several series, including the Personal/Biographical Series and the Manuscript Series. Baron's professional correspondence also includes many files that contain non-correspondence items such as reports, bills, budgets, grant applications, articles, and newspaper clippings. In going through the Baron Papers, the processors tried to sort out those files that were primarily correspondence and leave the others. Because of the size of the collection and the complexity of the materials, this division is somewhat arbitrary. Researchers may want to look at the subject series if they are interested in particular organizations with which Baron was involved. In the professional correspondence, the processors have tried to follow Baron's own filing system, which was a mixture of classification by subject and by date. Professional correspondence left unordered by Baron has been inserted at the closest and most logical point possible. Papers of Jeannette Baron, Baron's wife, are included here because her professional life was virtually inseparable from Baron's.
  In general this division contains correspondence with Baron's daughters, Tobey Baron Gitelle and Shoshana Baron Tancer, as well as with other relatives and family friends. Also included here are letters marking important life events, such as daughters' weddings, Baron's 60th, 70th, and 90th birthdays, his 50th wedding anniversary, and his wife's sickness and death. Baron's personal and professional lives were very much intertwined; many of his closest friends were colleagues. Thus it is sometimes difficult to make the distinction between "personal" and "professional" correspondence. Some personal correspondence is included with the professional correspondence, and some professional letters can be found with more personal ones.
  1-70 1928-1989 Mostly professional correspondence from Canaan files
  71-74 1907-1989 Mostly personal correspondence from Canaan files
  75-132 1930's- Mostly professional 1989 correspondence from New York files
  133-139 ca. 1920- Mostly personal correspondence 1989 from New York files
  140 all photos from correspondence
  - "A" - Incoming 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    American Jewish Congress
  - "B" - Incoming 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    D.S. Blondheim, A. Buechler
  - "C" - Incoming 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Curaorium der Kommerzienrat Fraenckel'schen Stiftungen, Cyclopedia Judaica
  - "D" - Incoming 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Dreschursky(?)
  - "E" - Incoming 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Z. Bllenberg, Bckhard, Encyclopaedia of the Social Sciences, I. Elbogen, Moses Binhorn
  - "F" - Incoming 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    B. Fischoff, Freimann
  - Friedman, P. - Incoming1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "G" - Incoming 1928 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "H" - Incoming 1930 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    C.L. Hirschfeld, S. Horovit
  - "J" - Incoming 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Jewish Theological Seminary of America
  - "K" - Incoming no date (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Julius Kravetz
  - "L" - Incoming no date (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Lewis
  - "M" - Incoming 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    S. Meisels, R. Miller, L.A. Mayer, Menorah Journal, A. Marx, J.A. Maynard, S.B. Maximon
  - "P" - Incoming 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    David Polish, D. Pearlman (Society for the Advancement of Judaism)
  - "R" - Incoming 1927-1930 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Ribelow, Royal Institute of International Affairs
  - Rappaport, Yosef -Incoming1830 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "S" - Incoming 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    A. Kohn, Schachter, H.W. Schneider, Shalom Speigel, Leo Schwarz, R. Szold
  - "T" - Incoming 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Talmudic Library, J. Tepper
  - "W" - Incoming 1927-1930 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    W. Waldmann, M. Waxer
  - Yemon, Max -Incoming1928 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "A" - Incoming 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    American Academy for Jewish Research, V. Aptowitzer, Dora Askomith, J. Augapfel, American Student Zionist Federation (AVUKAH)
  - "B" - Incoming 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Albert Baum, H. Bernstein, S. Bernstein, Dr. Bloch, D.S. Blondheim, Herbert Bloom, A. Buchler
  - "B" - Incoming 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Butler, Nicholas - Incoming 1929-1930
  - "C" - Incoming1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    S. Cohen, M.D. Casuto, B. Cohen, Collier's National Weekly
  - "C" - Incoming 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Columbia University - Incoming
  - "C" - Incoming 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Cyclopedia Judaica - Incoming Isaac Landman, editor
  - "D" - Incoming 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Israel Davidson
  - "D" - Incoming 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Damask, Emil -Incoming
  - "D" - Incoming 1930 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Diesendruk, Z. -Incoming
  - "E" - Incoming 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    M. Ekich, Israel Eitan, Elbogen, Cyclopedia Judaica, Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, Arno Erteschink
  - "F" - Incoming 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Frank Fackenthal, Samuel Feigin, Louis Finkelstein, A. Freiman
  - Friedmann, Filip - Incoming 1930 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "G" - Incoming 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Solomon Gandz, Geheimes Staats-Archiv, Richard Gottheil, Solomon Grayzel, Joshua Guttsman
  - "H" - Incoming 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    C. Hayes, B. Heller, G. Herlitz, Histadruth Ivrith, (Zvi Sharfstein, M.T. Tomash, D.B. Lechemi), S. Horowitz
  - "I" - Incoming 1930 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Walter Isaacs
  - "J" - Incoming 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Jewish Institute of Religion
  - "K" - Incoming 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    M. Kaplan, Max Kohier
  - Kohut, George Alexander - Incoming1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "L" - Incoming 1930 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    C. Levinthal, Loewinger
  - "M" - Incoming1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    J. Mann, Julian Mack, Menorah Journal, Menorah Association
  - "N"- Incoming 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Nachbeon, E. Neumann
  - "0" - Incomingno date (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Orient-Buchhandlung Heinz Lafaire K.-G.- Incoming1929 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - "P" - Incoming 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Samuel Penman, Martin Plotnick, David de Sola Pool
  - "Q" - Incoming 1930 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - "R - Incoming 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    H. Rothenberg, L.I. Riklis
  - "S' - Incoming 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Harry Sackler, Herbert Schneider, Society of Biblical Literature and Exegesis, J. Sonderling, M. Sussmann
  - Seligmann, Sigmund - Incoming 1930 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - "I" - Incoming 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    C. Tsviegel, Training School for Jewish Social Work (M.J. Karpf, director)
  - Torczyner, H. - Incoming 1930 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - "U" - Incoming 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    J. Unger, Josef Umanski
  - "W" - Incoming 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    James Waterman Wise (American Student Zionist Federation)
  - Wise, Stephen S. (SSW) - Incoming 1930 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - "Z" - Incoming 1929 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    Zeitshcrift fur die Geschichte der Juden in Deutsehiand
  - "A" - Outgoing 1928-1930 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    A. Altmann, Atlantic Express, Julius Augapfel
  - Apotowitzer, V. - Outgoing1930 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "B" - Outgoing1927-1930 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Bernstein, Eduard Beyer, D.S. Blondheim, Herbert Bloom, Walter Blumenthal, A. Buechler
  - Baron Family - Outgoing1930 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Butler, Nicholas Murry - Outgoing1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "C' - Outgoing 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Henry Cadbury, Boas Cohen, Elliot Cohen (Menorah Journal), Cyclopedia Judaica
  - "D" - Outgoing 1927-1928 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Israel Davidson, Drukarnia Lwowska
  - Damask, Emil - Outgoing1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Diesendruk, Zvi - Outgoing1928-1930 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "E" - Outgoing1925-1930 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Ismar Elbogen, Dr. Elzass, H.G. Enelow, Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, Erteschik
  - "F' - Outgoing 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Finkelstein, Adolf Fischhof, Heinrich Friedjung
  - Fachenthal, Frank D. - Outgoing1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Friedmann, Filip - Outgoing1927 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "G" - Outgoing 1925-1930 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Gandz, Geheimes Staatsarchiv, Ginzberg, Abram Goodman, Gottheil, Solomon Grayzel, Evarts Greene, Carl Grunberg, Walter de Gruyter
  - 'I" - Outgoing 1925-1930 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Otto Harrassowitz, J. Heinemann, C.L. Hirschfeld, Henry Hurwitz, Roger Howson
  - Hayes, Carlton - Outgoing1930 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Herlitz, Georg - Outgoing1925-1930 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Holzhausen, Adolf - Outgoing1927-1929 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - "I" - Outgoing 1930 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Nathan Isaacs
  - "J" - Outgoing1925-1930 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Vilctor Jacobsohn, Jewish Institute of Religion, Alvin Johnson, "Jvria", Siegfried Jakoby
  - "K" - Outgoing 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Dr. Karbach, M. Karpf, M. Kaplan, Max Kohler, Carl Kraeling, A. Kristianpoler, Maurice Kurnitsky
  - Klatzkin, Jacob - Outgoing1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Kobut, George Alexander - Outgoing1927-1930 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - "L" - Outgoing 1927-1930 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Isaac Landman, Lauterbach, I. Levitats, Librairie Lipsehutz, R. Lowit
  - "M" - Outgoing 1925-1930 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Margulies, Menorab Journal, Julian Morgenstern, I.G. Mudge
  - "N" - Outgoing 1930 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Allan Nevins, E. Neumann
  - "0" - Outgoing 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Orient-Buchhandlung Heinz Lafaire K.G.
  - "P' - Outgoing1925 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    R. Prager
  - "R" - Outgoing 1927-1930 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    Rappaport, Henry Rothenberg
  - "5" - Outgoing 1925-1930 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    Herbert Schneider, Sigmund Seligmann, Jacob Sonderling, Schmidt
  - "T" - Outgoing 1930 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    Dr. Torezyner
  - Trilling, Lionel - Outgoing1929 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - "W" - Outgoing 1927-1930 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    M.A. Wahrmann, Wieser, H. Wiesen, George Wolfe, S. Wise
  - Wise, James Waterman - Outgoing1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Wise, Stephen S. - Outgoing1928-1930 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - "Y-Z"- Outgoing 1925-1930 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    S. Zeitlin, Zionistisehe Landeskomitee
  - Miscellaneous - Outgoing1930 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Newspaper Articles no date (Box 3, Folder 38)
    The title of the article is "Sp. Prof. Dr. Jan Plasnik."
  - Baron - Outgoing 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Solomon Gandz, George Kohut, Herbert Bloom, Max Kohler, S. Krauss, Hans Rager
  - Baron - Outgoing 1928-1929 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Finkelstein, Kohut, Rothschild
  - Baron Memos 1927 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    J.X. Cohen, Stephen Wise, Louis Ginzberg
  - Miscellaneous 1927-1931 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    George Kohut, Samuel Teitelbaum, S.B. Maximon, Josef Lowenherz, Judge Mack
  - Miscellaneous 1928-1930 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Herbert Bloom, Jacob Sonderling, Max Kohler
  - Miscellaneous 1932 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Herbert Bloom, John Coss, Abraham Duker, Oskar Janowsky, Milton Steinberg, Louise Wise, Stephen Wise, outlines and booklists
  - Miscellaneous 1928-1930 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Notes, clippings, Max Kohler, Jewish Book of the Month Club, A. Marx, M. Kaplan
  - Miscellaneous 1929-1930 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Receipts, bulletins, minutes
  - Damask,Emil 1928-1932 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Diesendruk, Zvi 1926-1930 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Kohut, George Alexander 1928-1932 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Leflcowitz, David 1930-1931 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Margulies, Isider 1930-1931 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Newfield,Morris 1932 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Wise, Steven W. 1927-1930 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - "A" - Incoming 1931-1936 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Alice Angyal, Cyrus Adler, A.Z. Aescoly, W. Albright, Isaac Altman, American Friends of the Hebrew University (Rosenbach), American Inter-University Committee on Jewish Social Science, American Jewish Historical Socity, American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee, American Oriental Society, A. Aptowitzer, Dora Askowith, Julius Augapfel, Asaf, AVUKAH
  - "B" - Incoming 1932-1936 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Margarethe Bach, Baer, Majer Balaban, Samuel Baron (cousin), Barondess & Mushin (George Kohut), Herman Bernstein, S. Bernstein, Henry Besso, Ludwig Blau, Joseph Blau, Joshua Bloch, D. Blondheim, Herbert Bloom, Franz Boas, Ben Zion Bokser, L Borak
  - "B" - Incoming 1932-1936 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Abraham Brachman, A. Buehler, Max Bach - also includes insurance and book co. papers.
  - "C" - Incoming 1933-1937 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Frank Callcott, Umberto Cassuto, Israel Chipkin, Moths Cohen, Samuel Cohen, John Coss
  - "D" - Incoming1933-1937 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Emil Damask, Martin David, Israel Davidson, Diesendruk, A. Duker
  - "H" - Incoming 1932-1937 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Israel Efros, S. Ettinger, Ellenberg, Cyclopedia Judaica
  - "F" - Incoming 1932- 1937 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Frank Fackenthal, Samuel Feigin, Society of Friends of the Yiddish Scientific Institute, Joshua Finkel, Louis Finkelstein, Frank, David Frankel, Flip Friedman
  - "G" - Incoming 1933-1936 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    A. Galante, Solomon Gandz, N.M. Gelber, Joshua Goldberg, Israel Goldman, Nahum Goldmann, Harold Goldstein, Jacob Golub, Richard Gottheil, Graduate School for Jewish Social Work, Solomon Grayzel
  - "H" - Incoming 1931- 1936 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Jacob Halpern, Otto Harrassowitz, Henry Hurwitz (Meii~rah Journal), Hyman, B .H. Hartogensis, Philip Hayden, Hebrew Union College, Leo Heineman, Henry Hendricks (Maimonides Octocentennial), Henry Holt and Co., Hoogleeraren-Comite, Roger Howson (Librarian Columbia University), Hebrew Teachers College, Isaac Husik
  - "I-J" -Incoming 1931- 1936 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Oskar Janowsky, Jewish Center, Jewish Institute of Religion, Jewish People's University (Jewish Teachers Seminary and Peoples University), Leo Jung, Jewish Welfare Board
  - "K" - Incoming1932-1936 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Henry Kagan, H. Kallen, J. Kauffmann, Mordecai Kaplan, M. Karpf, Koeser, Hans Kelsen, Guido Kisch, Raymond Knox, Franz Kobler, A.S. Kohanski, Max Kohler, Hans Kohn, Mrs. A. Kohut, George Kohut, Samuel Krauss
  - "L" - Incoming 1934-1936 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Isaac Landman, Carl Landauer, League for Labor Palestine, Ada Lessing, Gershon Levi, Isaac Levitats, Beryl Levy, Louis Lipsky
  - "M" - Incoming 1932-1936 (Box 6, Folder 6)